Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
Today we've got an intermediate level lesson for you.
今天我们为大家准备了一节中级课程。
If you're interested in buying furniture for your house, you should like this lesson.
如果你对为家里买家具感兴趣，你会喜欢这节课的。
Exactly.
没错。
We are going to talk about a ton of different furniture items that you can get to decorate
我们将讨论大量不同的家具，你可以用它们来装饰
your house to make it all nice.
你的家，让它变得漂亮。
So we're going to talk about a lot of vocabulary today.
所以今天我们会学到很多词汇。
Pay attention while you're listening to some of the pieces of furniture that we talk about
听的时候注意我们提到的家具，
and we'll be back in a moment to talk more about them.
我们稍后会回来详细讨论它们。
How about this floor lamp?
这个落地灯怎么样？
Fine, just get it.
好吧，就买它吧。
We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
我们已经逛家具逛了五个小时了。
I'm so tired.
我好累。
We still need to find an armoire and a dresser.
我们还得找一个大衣柜和一个梳妆台。
Fine.
好吧。
I'm going to go home and drop off this nightstand, coffee table, and loveseat while you look
我打算回家，把这个床头柜、咖啡桌和双人沙发放下，你继续找
for the rest of the things.
剩下的东西。
Great.
太好了。
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a bean bag and a dining set.
大约一小时后接我，因为我想我也会买个豆袋椅和一套餐桌。
While you're at it, can you pick up a nice recliner?
顺便帮我买个舒服的躺椅吧？
I really want one so I can watch TV.
我真的很想要一个，这样就能看电视了。
Recliner?
躺椅？
In my beautifully decorated living room?
在我精心装饰的客厅里？
I don't think so.
想都别想。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now what we're going to do is since we have so much vocab, we're going to take a
所以现在我们要做的是，因为词汇量很大，我们会分两部分来
look at this language in two parts.
看这些语言点。
So now let's go to Language Takeaway Part 1.
现在让我们进入“语言要点”第一部分。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Okay, so everyone's heard of a lamp, a light.
好的，大家都听说过台灯、灯。
This is something that you use to read in the dark, for example, to see in the dark.
这是你在黑暗中阅读时用的东西，比如，用来在黑暗中看清东西。
But in this case we have a floor lamp.
但这里我们说的是落地灯。
So this is a lamp you put on the floor.
所以这是一种放在地上的灯。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
So usually this lamp would be a lot taller.
所以这种灯通常要高很多。
It'll maybe be like a meter taller, a meter and a half maybe.
可能有一米高，或者一米五左右。
Okay, so for example, in your living room next to your sofa, you might have a very tall
好的，比如，在你的客厅里，沙发旁边，你可能有一个很高的
floor lamp.
落地灯。
This allows you to get more light in the room.
这样能让房间里进更多光。
Right, so sometimes you know the center light in your living room is not enough.
对，有时候客厅中间那盏灯不够亮。
You want maybe more light in the corners, you get a little floor lamp.
你可能想在角落多些光，就放个小落地灯。
Okay, so that's the first item.
好，这是第一样东西。
Now that we go to the bedroom, we are getting an armoire.
现在我们到卧室，要买一个大衣橱。
Okay, an armoire.
好，大衣橱。
This is kind of like a wardrobe.
这有点像衣柜。
It's a piece of furniture we use to keep clothes in, but usually they're hanging clothes.
这是一种用来放衣服的家具，但通常是挂着的衣服。
Okay, so a closet is usually inside a wall, right?
好，所以壁橱通常是嵌在墙里的，对吧？
Right, so a closet's a part of your house.
对，壁橱是房子的一部分。
It's not furniture.
它不是家具。
Right, so an armoire is the same as a closet, but it's not in the house, like in the walls.
对，所以大衣橱和壁橱一样，但它不在房子里，不像嵌在墙里那种。
It's outside.
它是独立的。
It's a piece of furniture.
它是一件家具。
It's a big box.
是个大箱子。
Yeah, I could pick it up and move it.
对，我可以搬起来移动它。
Okay.
好。
Yes, so an armoire is a tall place to keep clothing.
是的，所以大衣橱是个高的地方用来放衣服。
Usually you hang your clothes.
通常你把衣服挂起来。
You hang your shirts and your dresses and your coats.
挂你的衬衫、裙子和外套。
And moving on, we have a dresser.
接下来，我们有一个梳妆台。
Now this seems pretty straightforward.
这个看起来挺直接的。
To get dressed, you have a dresser.
要穿衣服，你就用梳妆台。
Yeah, it makes a lot of sense, but there is a big difference here between an armoire and
是的，这很有道理，但这里有一个很大的区别，就是大衣柜和
a dresser.
梳妆台。
A dresser is usually drawers.
梳妆台通常是有抽屉的。
So you keep your sweaters, your shirts, your socks, your underwear in a dresser.
所以你把毛衣、衬衫、袜子、内衣都放在梳妆台里。
Okay, so an armoire, as you said, usually you hang your shirts or your pants.
好的，所以大衣柜，就像你说的，通常是挂衬衫或裤子。
It's for hanging stuff only.
它只用来挂东西。
A dresser is you have different drawers where you can put your socks, your boxer shorts,
梳妆台有不同抽屉，你可以放袜子、平角内裤
and any other things that you keep.
和其他你存放的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So two very handy words, and that's what makes the difference between a closet.
所以这两个很实用的词，这就是它们和壁橱的区别。
So many people say, oh, it's just a closet.
很多人会说，哦，那只是个壁橱。
Well, a closet's different.
嗯，壁橱是不同的。
No, a closet is actually part of your house.
不，壁橱实际上是房子的一部分。
It's a part of the wall.
它是墙的一部分。
Maybe it has a door.
可能它有门。
Yeah, there's a big difference there.
是的，这里有很大的区别。
Okay.
好的。
So moving on, we have a nightstand that's also usually in the bedroom.
那么接下来，我们有一个床头柜，通常也在卧室里。
That's right.
没错。
So I always wondered, why is it called a nightstand and not a daystand?
我一直好奇，为什么它叫床头柜，而不是“白天柜”？
Well, a nightstand, it makes sense.
嗯，床头柜这个名字挺有道理的。
It usually has a lamp on it, a light on it.
它上面通常放着一盏灯，一个照明灯。
And so when you're in bed and you want to read, you have a nightstand next to you to
所以当你躺在床上想看书时，旁边有个床头柜
put your lamp so you can turn the lamp on.
放你的灯，这样你就可以开灯。
Usually I also keep my books here.
我通常也会把书放在这里。
So when I'm reading, I put my books down, then I go to sleep.
所以当我读书时，我把书放下，然后睡觉。
Some people also keep their glasses and their alarm clock on a nightstand.
有些人还会把眼镜和闹钟放在床头柜上。
It's a small table that stands next to your bed.
它是一个放在床边的小桌子。
Very good.
非常好。
And our last word for language takeaway part one, we have a coffee table.
我们语言要点第一部分的最后一个词是咖啡桌。
Okay.
好的。
So with the coffee table, Marco, we're moving back into the living room.
说到咖啡桌，Marco，我们又回到了客厅。
And in the living room, you have a sofa, you have some chairs.
在客厅里，你有沙发，有一些椅子。
You need a table, but you don't want a big table.
你需要一张桌子，但你不想要大桌子。
You want a small table or a very short table.
你想要一张小桌子或很矮的桌子。
This is a coffee table.
这就是咖啡桌。
It's called a coffee table.
它叫咖啡桌。
I'm not really sure why.
我不太确定为什么。
I guess because if you're having coffee in the living room, this is where you put the
我猜是因为如果你在客厅喝咖啡，这就是你放
coffee.
咖啡的地方。
That's right.
没错。
And we even have something called coffee table books.
我们甚至还有叫咖啡桌书的东西。
These are big, beautiful books, hardback books that have many pictures that you put on your
这些是又大又漂亮的书，精装书，有很多图片，你放在
coffee table to look nice.
咖啡桌上，看起来很美观。
It's not for you to actually read all the time.
不是让你一直读的。
Well, I read them, but it's more important to use these books to look nice.
嗯，我读它们，但更重要的是用这些书来装饰。
This is interesting though, because in many other countries, they're not really called
不过有趣的是，在很多其他国家，它们并不真的叫
a coffee table.
咖啡桌。
A direct translation wouldn't really help you in many cases.
直接翻译在很多情况下帮不了你。
I think in Chinese, it's called a tea table, not a coffee table.
我想在中文里，它叫茶几，而不是咖啡桌。
It makes sense.
有道理。
Right?
对吧？
I know in Spanish, it's just called a center table.
我知道在西班牙语里，它就叫中心桌。
Okay.
好的。
So this is basically the low table you have in your living room next to your sofa, in
所以这基本上是你客厅里放在沙发旁边的那张矮桌子，
front of your sofa actually, so you can have tea or coffee and read books.
实际上是在沙发前面，这样你可以喝茶或咖啡，看书。
Or put your feet up while you're watching TV.
或者在看电视时把脚翘起来。
Not in my house when I was a kid.
我小时候在我家可不行。
All right.
好吧。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be returning a little bit
我们为什么不回去，再听一遍对话，然后我们会回来
with more vocab.
讲更多词汇。
How about this floor lamp?
这个落地灯怎么样？
Fine.
行。
Just get it.
买吧。
We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
我们已经逛家具逛了五个小时了。
I'm so tired.
我好累。
We still need to find an armoire and a dresser.
我们还需要找一个大衣橱和一个梳妆台。
Fine.
行。
I'm going to go home and drop off this nightstand, coffee table, and loveseat while you look
我要回家放下这个床头柜、咖啡桌和双人沙发，你继续找
for the rest of the things.
剩下的东西。
Great.
太好了。
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a beanbag and a dining set.
大约一小时后接我，因为我想我还会买一个豆袋椅和一套餐桌椅。
While you're at it, can you pick up a nice recliner?
既然你在忙，能帮我买个舒服的躺椅吗？
I really want one so I can watch TV.
我真的很想要一个，这样我可以看电视。
Recliner?
躺椅？
In my beautifully decorated living room?
在我装修精美的客厅里？
I don't think so.
想都别想。
All right.
好了。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now, let's take a look at Language Takeaway Part 2.
现在，让我们看看语言要点第二部分。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Coming up, we have one of my favorite phrases in the English language.
接下来，我们有英语里我最喜欢的短语之一。
I don't know why I like it so much, but it is a great name for a piece of furniture.
我不知道为什么这么喜欢它，但它是一个家具的好名字。
A loveseat.
双人沙发。
Loveseat.
Okay.
好的。
It sounds very romantic.
听起来很浪漫。
It does.
确实。
A loveseat.
双人沙发。
Well, think about a sofa.
嗯，想想沙发。
A sofa can be very large.
沙发可以很大。
You can have four or five people on a sofa.
你可以让四五个人坐在沙发上。
Right.
对。
But a loveseat is a small sofa for two people.
但双人沙发是供两个人坐的小沙发。
Okay.
好的。
So that's what makes the difference, right?
这就是区别所在，对吧？
It's a sofa, but only two people can sit on this.
这是一张沙发，但只能坐两个人。
That's right.
没错。
So a sofa, it's not a loveseat.
所以是沙发，不是双人沙发。
And what about if it's one, because usually sofa sets, you have a loveseat, a big one,
那如果只有一个座位呢？因为通常沙发套装里，会有一个双人沙发、一个大沙发，
and you have one, sometimes an individual one.
还有一个单人沙发。
Do you just call that a chair?
你就直接叫它椅子吗？
Yep.
是的。
A chair.
椅子。
Okay.
好的。
Exactly.
没错。
We'll come to it in a minute.
我们一会儿会讲到这个。
There's a special kind of chair that it might be, but we're not quite there yet.
有一种特殊的椅子可能属于这类，但我们还没讲到那里。
First, we have another kind of chair, which is very special and reminds me a lot of the
首先，我们有另一种椅子，非常特别，让我想起很多
1970s.
1970年代。
Right.
对。
We have a bean bag, and this is actually a piece of furniture that's still very popular
我们有豆袋椅，这实际上是一种在很多地方仍然很受欢迎的家具。
in many places.
And it's called a bean bag because it's a huge bag that is filled with beans.
它叫豆袋椅，因为这是一个装满豆子的大袋子。
Right.
对。
Beans or something soft.
豆子或柔软的东西。
And when you sit on it, it looks like a ball, but when you sit on it, it can change shape.
当你坐上去时，它看起来像个球，但坐上去后可以改变形状。
Right.
对。
It molds to what shape you are.
它会根据你的体型塑形。
And usually they're very light.
而且通常它们很轻。
A lot of times, I hate to say it, a lot of times bachelors' apartments have these.
很多时候，我讨厌这么说，很多单身公寓里都有这些。
That's right.
没错。
It's actually a very cheap piece of furniture, and it's comfortable.
这其实是一种很便宜的家具，而且很舒服。
Sometimes if you're watching TV, you can just sit on your bean bag and watch TV.
有时候如果你在看电视，就可以坐在豆袋椅上看电视。
Even I know some people may fall asleep on a bean bag as guests.
我甚至知道有些人作为客人会在豆袋椅上睡着。
I've never slept on, well, maybe once, but I don't remember sleeping on a bean bag.
我从来没在豆袋椅上睡过，嗯，也许有一次，但我不记得在上面睡过。
I imagine it's quite uncomfortable.
我想那应该很不舒服。
Yeah, for your back.
是啊，对背不好。
But moving on after a bean bag, which is a good informal piece of furniture, we have
但继续往下说，豆袋椅是一种不错的休闲家具，之后我们有
a dining set, which is a lot nicer.
一套餐桌椅，那就好多了。
Okay, dining set.
好的，餐桌椅套装。
All right.
好的。
So a dining set has many pieces.
所以一套餐桌椅有很多件。
You have a dining room table.
你有一张餐桌。
Right.
对。
And you have chairs.
还有椅子。
So a set is basically a collection of a table and chairs together.
所以一套基本上就是桌子和椅子的组合。
Sometimes I think it will also include some type of piece of furniture that's next to
有时候我觉得它还会包括一些放在餐桌旁边的家具，用来放盘子、茶杯之类的。
the dining table where you can keep your plates and you can keep your teacups and all that.
What's that called?
那叫什么？
That's called a buffet.
那叫餐具柜。
And that's basically, it's like a dresser for your dining room.
基本上，它就像餐厅里的梳妆台。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
It's got like drawers and stuff for your plates, your cups, like you said, and it's next to
它有抽屉之类的东西，用来放盘子、杯子，就像你说的，而且它放在
the dining room table.
餐桌旁边。
But the dining room set or the dining set is for the dining room.
但餐厅套装或餐桌椅套装是用于餐厅的。
It's the table where you eat dinner.
就是吃饭用的桌子。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
And now moving on to that special chair that I am a big fan of.
现在继续讲那种我很喜欢的特殊椅子。
It's very comfortable to sit on and it's called a recliner.
坐上去非常舒服，它叫躺椅。
So we have a word here, recline.
我们这里有个词，recline。
It means to lie back, to put your head back, to get comfortable.
意思是向后靠，把头往后仰，让自己舒服。
So a recliner is a chair that you can change the shape of to make you lie down flat.
所以躺椅是一种可以改变形状，让你平躺下来的椅子。
So when you sit down, you're sitting, but what if you want to lie down in a chair?
所以当你坐下时，你是坐着的，但如果你想在椅子上躺下呢？
This chair lets you do that.
这把椅子就能让你做到。
And it also, from the bottom part where your feet are, a little thing pops up so you can
而且，在你脚放的地方，底部会弹出一个东西，这样你就可以
rest your feet on top of this little extension of the chair.
把脚放在椅子的这个小延伸部分上。
Okay, so it has a built-in footrest.
好的，所以它有一个内置的脚凳。
Footrest, exactly.
脚凳，没错。
So it's very comfortable.
所以它非常舒服。
It's very popular.
它非常受欢迎。
If you ever watch the series Friends, they have the recliners.
如果你看过《老友记》，他们就有躺椅。
It's very comfortable to watch sports, for example.
比如看体育比赛时坐上去很舒服。
You have your beer.
你拿着啤酒。
Joey has his recliner.
乔伊有他的躺椅。
And remember when Joey and Chandler lived together, they have the two recliners in front
还记得乔伊和钱德勒住在一起时，他们有两把躺椅放在
of the TV.
电视前面。
Those chairs are recliners and they're very, very popular.
那些椅子就是躺椅，非常非常受欢迎。
Actually I think in the United States, they're very commonly known by the brand, Lazy Boy.
实际上，我觉得在美国，它们通常以品牌“懒人椅”而闻名。
That's right.
没错。
There's a brand.
有一个品牌。
It's not a kind of furniture, but it's the name of the brand.
它不是一种家具类型，而是品牌名称。
It's Lazy Boy and they're very, very famous.
就是“懒人椅”，它们非常非常有名。
You're right, Marco, for their reclining chairs.
马可，你说得对，它们以躺椅闻名。
Exactly.
没错。
So Lazy Boys, you may hear it, but the real word for it is called a recliner.
所以“Lazy Boys”，你可能听过这个词，但它的正式名称叫“躺椅”。
So a lot of interesting pieces of furniture there.
那里有很多有趣的家具。
I think our house is going to look amazing.
我觉得我们的房子会看起来很棒。
So why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time.
那我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
How about this floor lamp?
这个落地灯怎么样？
Fine.
好吧。
Just get it.
买就买吧。
We have been shopping for furniture for five hours.
我们已经逛家具逛了五个小时了。
I'm so tired.
我好累。
We still need to find an armoire and a dresser.
我们还得找一个大衣橱和一个梳妆台。
Fine.
好吧。
I'm going to go home and drop off this nightstand, coffee table, and loveseat while you look
我要回家放下这个床头柜、咖啡桌和双人沙发，你继续找
for the rest of the things.
剩下的东西。
Great.
太好了。
Pick me up in about an hour because I think I'll also get a beanbag and a dining set.
大约一小时后接我，因为我想我还会买个豆袋椅和一套餐桌椅。
While you're at it, can you pick up a nice recliner?
顺便帮我买个舒服的躺椅吧？
I really want one so I can watch TV.
我真的很想要一个，这样我就能看电视了。
Recliner?
躺椅？
In my beautifully decorated living room?
放在我装修精美的客厅里？
I don't think so.
想都别想。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about furniture, it's very interesting.
说到家具，这挺有意思的。
How do you take it home?
你怎么把它带回家？
What do you do?
你怎么办？
In this case, they were transporting it themselves.
在这个例子里，他们自己运输。
The guy said, I'm going to go home and drop off this nightstand, coffee table, and loveseat.
那个人说：“我要回家放下这个床头柜、咖啡桌和双人沙发。”
So to drop off.
所以“drop off”。
Okay, this is a great verb.
好，这是个很棒的动词。
To drop off.
“Drop off”。
It's a verbal phrase.
这是一个动词短语。
So the preposition there is off, not on.
所以介词是“off”，不是“on”。
So I could say, for example, Marco, I'm just going to drop off my bag at home and then
比如，Marco，我先把包放回家，然后
I'll meet you guys for dinner.
再和你们一起吃晚饭。
That means I'm going to go to my house and put down my bag and then I'll leave.
意思是，我回家放下包，然后离开。
So to drop off is basically to go somewhere so you can put something in that place.
所以“drop off”基本上就是去某个地方，把东西放在那里。
But it doesn't mean that you're going to go to that place and stay there.
但这并不意味着你要去那个地方并待在那里。
So if I say, I'm going to drop off the kids at school, that means I'm going to take the
所以如果我说“我要去送孩子上学”，意思是，我把
kids and leave them at school and then go away.
孩子送到学校，然后离开。
It doesn't mean you're going to school yourself.
这并不意味着你自己也要上学。
So can you drop off the laundry at the dry cleaners, please?
所以，你能把衣服送到干洗店吗？
Very good.
很好。
So drop off the laundry to the dry cleaners, leave it there and then go somewhere else.
所以“drop off”就是把衣服送到干洗店，放在那里，然后去别的地方。
So what happens at three o'clock when the kids are still at school?
那三点钟孩子还在学校时会发生什么？
That's right.
没错。
Now we use the opposite verbal phrase and that is to pick up.
现在我们用相反的动词短语，那就是“pick up”。
Okay, drop off, pick up.
好，“drop off”和“pick up”。
So you go pick up the kids.
所以你去接孩子。
You go pick up the laundry.
你去取衣服。
So this isn't just about picking something up from a table or the ground.
所以这不只是从桌子或地上捡起东西。
You can actually use your car to pick something up.
你实际上可以用车去取东西。
Right.
对。
You go and retrieve it.
你去取回来。
So I'm going to the post office to pick up my package.
所以我要去邮局取我的包裹。
Very good.
很好。
So phrases that you're going to have to use if you're talking about furniture, if you're
所以这些短语你在谈论家具或
talking about buying something.
买东西时都会用到。
And while we're on the topic, I know that one of the most popular places to buy furniture
说到这个话题，我知道买家具最受欢迎的地方之一
is Ikea.
是宜家。
Are you a big fan of Ikea?
你是宜家的忠实粉丝吗？
I like Ikea and I love what they've done for people who don't want to spend too much money
我喜欢宜家，也欣赏他们为那些不想在家具上花太多钱的人
on furniture.
所做的贡献。
Furniture is expensive.
家具很贵。
Furniture is very expensive.
家具非常贵。
You can spend $5,000 on a sofa.
你可以花5000美元买一张沙发。
And so Ikea is a wonderful brand and I think a wonderful company because it makes good-looking
所以宜家是一个很棒的品牌，也是一家很棒的公司，因为它让好看的
furniture affordable.
家具变得价格合理。
And it's because you put it together yourself, right?
而且这是因为你得自己组装，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A lot of things you have to assemble or put together by yourself.
很多东西你得自己组装或拼装。
So you buy it in a box and then you make it.
所以你买的是盒子里的东西，然后自己制作。
It's a little bit frustrating sometimes, but for people like me, and I'm sure people like
有时候有点让人沮丧，但对我这样的人，我相信像你这样的人，
you, part of the fun is putting stuff together.
乐趣的一部分就是拼装东西。
Yeah, because you kind of feel like you kind of built it, but you really didn't.
是啊，因为你会有种自己建造了它的感觉，但其实并没有。
So it kind of gives you that false sense of accomplishment.
所以这给了你一种虚假的成就感。
It's like I'm in the 19th century and I can make my own furniture.
就像我身处19世纪，能自己做家具一样。
So it's very popular.
所以它很受欢迎。
And apart from having great furniture, I understand that they have amazing meatballs.
除了有很棒的家具，我知道他们还有美味的肉丸。
They do.
是的。
Well, I'm a Swedish.
嗯，我是瑞典人。
I never get to eat Swedish meatballs.
我从来都吃不到瑞典肉丸。
And here in China, they do have some of the better meatballs around.
在中国这里，确实有一些比较好的肉丸。
So I would recommend if you haven't tried them, try them.
所以我建议，如果你还没尝过，就去试试吧。
They're pretty good.
它们挺好吃的。
Yeah, go to IKEA.
是啊，去宜家吧。
Go to IKEA, have some dinner.
去宜家，吃顿晚餐。
Let me know.
告诉我你的感受。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Do you like IKEA and do you love their meatballs?
你喜欢宜家吗？你爱他们的肉丸吗？
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候在那儿见。
Bye.
再见。
Go to our website.
去我们的网站看看吧。